# Alim Satria Fi'i Wijaya Kusuma

HARDWARE ENGINEER · PCB DESIGNER

Sleman Regency, Yogyakarta, Indonesia

🗷 alimsatria45@outlook.com | 🏠 justraven.github.io/portfolio | 🖸 github.com/justraven | 🛅 linkedin.com/in/alimsatria

### **Personal Profile**

A student at Universitas Gadjah Mada specializing in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology with a strong passion for Control Systems and Hardware Engineering. They actively engage in diverse projects related to instrumentation and control systems, including coding microcontrollers, designing PCBs, and documenting projects using LaTEX and GitHub.

## **Education**

**Universitas Gadjah Mada** 

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Undergraduate degree in Instrumentation and Control Engineering Technology

2021 - Current

**Universitas Gadjah Mada** 

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Associate degree in Instrumentation Technology

2017 - 2021

# Work Experience \_

#### PT. Integrasi Teknologi Unggas (BroilerX)

Yoqyakarta, Indonesia

Hardware Engineer

Jan 2021 - Mar 2022

- Developed an IoT devices to monitor the environment of broiler house.
- Responsible for the PCB design process, creating prototypes, communicating and collaborating on IoT integration in the device, and ensuring the device operates effectively.
- Technical Skills: PCB Design using KiCAD, Firmware programming using C++, Internet of Things
- Soft Skills: Teamwork, Time Management, Communication.

# **University Projects**

#### Implementation of Flight Controller Design and PID Control on Quadrotor Attitude

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022 - Current

- Make and iterate PCB design of quadrotor flight controller to find the most compact and stable design using 8-bit microcontroller
- Tuning and refining the quadrotor attitude control using PID to make a stable attitude control and add feature to the program to log the IMU sensor and GPS data
- Technical skill: PCB design using KiCAD, Programinng in Processing (Java), control system

#### Remake of Feedback ES151

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Undergraduate

Dec 2022

- Revive and repair an old Feedback ES151 so that it can be used for learning and demonstrating PID to control velocity and position of a DC Motor
- Designing Human Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView so the machine could interact and be controlled by a computer
- Code the microcontroller using C++ and bridge the communication between the computer (HMI) and the machine
- Technical skill: Programming in C++, Building HMI with LabView

# Design and Implementation of Light Ambient Control System on Broiler Farm Using PID Controller

Yogyakarta, Indonesia

Universitas Gadjah Mada - Assosiate

2020

- Creating a device to maintain constant light intensity inside broiler chicken cages. The device consists of a microcontroller connected to a light sensor and LED.
- Designing Human Machine Interface (HMI) using LabView so the machine could interact and be controlled by an web app over the internet
- Technical skill: PCB Design using EAGLE, Firmware programming using C++

#### Skills

**Programming** 

Python, LabView, C/C++, Matlab.

**Hardware Design** 

Kicad, Eagle

**Soft Skills** Teamwork, Problem-solving, Documentation.

## **Interests**

JUNE 20, 2023

Since 2017, I have been in love with Linux. I use it for coding and doing hardware design. My distro of choice is KDE

Neon because it is beautiful

I write some projects on my GitHub about control systems and hardware design. One of my favorite projects is when I revive an old PID tuning machine for the control system lab. I build the HMI with LabView and code for the

main controller with C++. kindly check out the documentation of the project here.

LateX I love LaTEX for writing my lab report because it looks pretty, cool and neat. I go as far as make a lab report

template. Kindly check out my template here.

# Languages\_

**English** Professional proficiency (TOEFL ITP Score : 567/677)

IndonesianNative proficiencyJavaneseNative proficiency